Isaac M. Jordan – Software Engineer

Glasgow, United Kingdom IsaacJordan95@gmail.com

http://isaacjordan.me http://uk.linkedin.com/in/ijordan http://github.com/sheepzez

Objective

Professional software engineer with 4 years experience in small and large enterprise environments building innovative products aiming to be market leaders. Experienced in a variety of languages and technology stacks, mostly recently with Java, JavaScript, TypeScript, and AWS services (Lambda, EC2, SQS, DynamoDB, S3).

Work Experience

Amazon Edinburgh, UK

Software Development Engineer II

Sep 2018 - Present

- Integrated my team's video rendering API with a large Amazon Advertising product which involved collaborating with engineers and UX designers in Seattle over several months. Developed a new serverless micro-service to act as a mediator, created and integrated new TypeScript React components in another team's code, and set up automated alarming and monitoring.
- Actively worked to improve my team's development and release process over time such as introducing SonarQube for code quality analysis which has improved our quality month-on-month.
- Introduced tools to monitor our operational load as a team (week-on-week tracking of ticket counts).

Amazon Edinburgh, UK

 $igcup Software\ Development\ Engineer\ I$

Sep 2017 - Sep 2018

- Launched a new video advertising program and increased performance by 10x in 6 months through rigorous experimentation, exceeding our team goal of \$500k sales.
- Improved customer privacy by developing a micro-service to scrub personally indentifiable information from logs within seconds, far exceeding the quality of previous batch-based systems
- Improved management and discoverability of projects in my team's system by developing new React components. Added a new front-end test harness to test code that was previously untested, using Enzyme for shallow rendering.

Amazon Edinburgh, UK

Software Development Engineer Intern

Jun 2016 - Aug 2017

- Created a prototype application with the goal of applying personalised video to existing content in a
 fast and automated fashion. It utilised multithreading to process images in real-time with OpenCV.
- Developed skills in dealing with ambiguity and creating solutions where there is no prior art.

TBR Global Chauffeuring

Glasgow, UK

Software Developer (Intern, followed by Part-Time)

Jun 2015 - May 2016

- Improved ingestion time of data from Emirates Airline from hours of manual effort to minutes by creating a system to retrieve, parse and visualise XML files from FTP servers which validated data using OpenAddressesUK and GoogleMaps.
- Worked on long-term projects, such as creating a web-based geofence manager using C#, MVC.NET, JavaScript, and MapBox software.

Chi Squared Innovations

Remote

Software Developer (Part-Time)

Sep 2014 - Jun 2015

- Worked closely with CEO to recreate the public facing website in-house using the Python/Django web-stack, along with D3.js data visualisation library.

Education

University of Glasgow

Glasgow, UK

BSc (Hons) in Computer Science (First Class)

2013 - 2017

- Level 3 Class Prize Strong A grades in all Computer Science classes, and many Mathematics classes.
- First Prize at Glasgow University Tech Society Hackathon 2015.